Rules are made to be broken.
The Transporter is a action, crime, thriller film directed by Corey Yuen.
Former Special Forces officer Frank Martin will deliver anything to anyone for the
right price, and his no-questions-asked policy puts him in high demand.
But when he realizes his latest cargo is alive, it sets
in motion a dangerous chain of events.
The bound and gagged Lai is being smuggled to France by a shady American businessman, and Frank
works to save her as his own illegal activities are uncovered by a French detective.
Frank Martin, played by Jason Statham.
Lai, played by Shu Qi.
Tarconi, played by François Berléand.
Wall Street, played by Matt Schulze.
Mr Kwai, played by Ric Young.
Leader, played by Doug Rand.
The Transporter (French: Le Transporteur) is a 2002 English-language French action film directed by
Louis Leterrier and Corey Yuen from a screenplay by Luc Besson and Robert Mark Kamen.
It is the first installment in the Transporter franchise and stars Jason Statham in
the title role, alongside Shu Qi, François Berléand and Matt Schulze.
In the film, Frank Martin, a British mercenary driver living in
France, finds himself involved in a human trafficking plot.
The Transporter premiered at the Regency Village Theatre in Los Angeles on October 2, 2002, and was first theatrically released in the United
States on October 11, 2002, by 20th Century Fox, in France on 23 October by EuropaCorp, and in the UK on January 17, 2003.
It received mixed reviews from critics with praise for its
action sequences and Statham's performance.
It grossed $43.9 million worldwide and was followed
by a sequel, Transporter 2, in 2005.
The film explores themes of martial arts, transporter,
france, human trafficking, organized crime.
The tone is intense.